TERRA JULY RILEY

Analyst, EDA Expert, Web Scraper & API Aficionado

(415) 635-9770 | Oakland, CA 94609 | terrajriley@gmail.com github.com/TerraJRiley | linkedin.com/in/terra-j-riley

PROFILE SUMMARY

While I've always had a thirst for knowledge, data science has been my one true love both for the craft & the opportunity it presents to learn about the world and the people around me. I pair my data skillset with my background in communications, psychology & economics to help clients and companies discover profitable insights from their data.

SKILLS & TOOLS

Data Visualization: Tableau, Matplotlib, Google Sheets Visualizations, Seaborn

Machine Learning: Linear & Logistic Regression, K-Nearest Neighbors, Unsupervised Clustering, Neural Networks, etc.

Languages: Python, SQL

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Web Scraping & APIs (Various Projects)

10/2018 - 01/2019

- Utilized Selenium, Requests and BeautifulSoup libraries to gather information from Google, Craigslist, The Overwatch Forums and ChubbyGrub, both out of curiosity and to sharpen my skills.
- Also learned and used the Youtube, Reddit and Nutritionix APIs for the same purposes.

Youtube Toxicity (Concept Project)

10/2018 - 11/2018

- I was curious if the youtube comment was as toxic and terrible as people said that they were. Furthermore I was curious if, should toxicity be present, if said negativity was related to the communities that creators fostered.
- At the time I got the sense that most comment sections aren't toxic, but very supportive of the creators they follow.
- Executed work with Textblob sentimizer, Youtube API, latent dirichlet allocation and natural language processing.

General Assembly Data Science Immersive

San Francisco, CA

Data Science Student

08/2018 - 10/2018

- Full-time immersive student with 400+ hours of instruction in analyzing data sets for insights and presenting findings using statistics, programming, data modeling and business knowledge.
- Utilized the reddit API to obtain and explore data about specific subreddit communities to analyze sexism[].
- Learned the Youtube API to understand the sentiment of each channel's community.

Zeterre Landscape Architecture

San Francisco, CA

Web & Brand Designer

01/2018 - 06/2018

- Organized questionnaire database and provided useful insights from the data collected.
- Cleaned and organized content library and marketing databases resulting in easier use of these tools for the team.
- Worked with the owner and project leads to create multiple new websites from scratch.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Wicked Grounds Cafe

Shift Lead

San Francisco, CA 06/2012 - 12/2017

Optimized ShopKeep system interface for increased ease of barista operation.

- Assisted manager in developing and implementing operational procedures to improve service quality.
- Opened and closed shop, which included counting and managing money.

San Francisco Citadel

San Francisco, CA

House Manager 10/2011 - 12/2015

- Managed, supported and educated volunteers on their duties to ensure smooth operations for the Citadel.
- Responsible for managing payment of Citadel staff members.

EDUCATION

City College of San Francisco

08/2013 - 06/2017

A.A. Degrees in Communications, Psychology, Economics, Social & Behavioral Science, Math & Science, Arts & Humanities